Hey, catch her!
이봐, 잡아!
MUNDANE
평범한
There are
있다
no security cameras here, are there?
여기 보안 카메라는 없어요, 그렇죠?
Run!
달리다!
Jo Anna?
조안나?
Your kind always thinks having superpowers solves everything.
너희 종족은 항상 생각한다 초능력을 가지면 모든 것이 해결됩니다.
As if you ever did anything productive or paid taxes with them.
마치 생산적인 일을 해본 적이 있는 것처럼 또는 그들과 함께 세금을 납부했습니다.
Where are your friends?
친구들은 어디에 있나요?
Why do you make me do the same thing over and over?
왜 나한테 그러게 만드는 거야? 같은 일이 계속 반복되나요?
I'll roast you to a crisp.
바삭바삭하게 구워줄게요.
Didn't you check the weather?
날씨를 확인하지 않았나요?
It's raining.
비가 온다.
Do you know what's stronger than a superpower in modern society?
무엇이 더 강한지 아시나요? 현대 사회의 초강대국보다?
It's power.
힘이다.
She's right.
그녀 말이 맞아요.
Having "super" in front doesn't imply greater power.
앞에 "super"가 있는 경우 더 큰 힘을 의미하지는 않습니다.
If anything, it's more like
어쨌든 그것은 마치
the relationship between gochujang and chogochujang.
고추장의 관계 그리고초고추장.
Or perhaps a fly
아니면 파리
and a fruit fly.
그리고 초파리
What I'm trying to say is
내가 말하려는 것은
that I'm screwed.
내가 망했다고.
MISSING PERSON
실종자
LEE HWA-JIN, AGE 23 LAST SEEN AT JONGNO NAKSIN STATION
이화진, 23세 종로낙신역에서 마지막으로 본 모습
Has it been a week since we last heard from Hwa-jin?
일주일 됐나? 지난번에 화진이한테 소식을 들은 이후로요?
Yes.
예.
Bun-mi, you should learn to control the anger within you.
분미야, 배워야 해 당신 안에 있는 분노를 통제하기 위해.
I'm working on it.
나는 그것을 위해 노력하고 있습니다.
Thought you were on a diet.
다이어트 중이신 줄 알았어요.
I eat one meal a day.
나는 하루에 한 끼를 먹습니다.
I can eat whatever I want for that one meal.
내가 먹고 싶은 건 뭐든 먹을 수 있어 그 한 끼 식사를 위해.
You had dinner with me earlier.
아까 나랑 저녁 먹었잖아.
This is dessert.
이것은 디저트입니다.
And you drink alcohol every day too.
그리고 당신도 매일 술을 마십니다.
- Wow, what's that? - This.
- 와, 그게 뭐죠? - 이.
- It's crazy! - Did you see it?
- 미친 짓이야! - 봤어?
Hey, everyone. Do you see that?
안녕하세요 여러분. 저거 보이나요?
- He's completely reckless. - He's pulling the bus up.
- 그 사람 완전 무모해요. - 그는 버스를 세우고 있습니다.
He's like Superman. I mean, Spider-Man!
그는 슈퍼맨 같아요. 내 말은, 스파이더맨!
- Hey. - Oh, it's zoomed in.
- 안녕. - 아, 확대됐네요.
Wow, he's pulled it up!
와, 그 사람이 뽑아냈구나!
- Amazing! - He ended up getting arrested.
- 놀랍습니다! - 결국 체포됐어요.
We're watching the birth of a hero!
영웅의 탄생을 지켜보고 있다!
The things falling from him are coins, aren't they?
그에게서 떨어지는 것들 동전인가요?
- Yes. - Everyone, this is 100% real.
- 예. - 여러분, 이건 100% 실화입니다.
We have something like that among our kind?
우리에겐 그런 게 있어요 우리 중에?
Back in the day.
옛날로 돌아가서.
Let's go get him.
그를 잡으러 가자.
Drive...
운전...
- You drive. - What?
- 당신이 운전해요. - 무엇?
No, I can't. I need to start my shift. Later.
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다. 교대근무를 시작해야 해요. 나중에.
A lot of people are probably after him.
아마 그를 쫓는 사람이 많을 것이다.
We must find him first.
먼저 그를 찾아야 해요.
Hold on!
기다리다!
Just wait a moment.
잠시만 기다리세요.
We'll end up getting caught. You said a lot of people are after him.
우리는 결국 잡힐 것이다. 그를 쫓는 사람이 많다고 하더군요.
If we run into them while Hwa-jin's not even with us...
우리가 그들과 마주치면 화진이는 우리랑도 없는 사이에...
The two of us are no match for them.
우리 둘은 그들과 상대가 되지 않습니다.
Bun-mi!
분미!
This guy is different.
이 사람은 다릅니다.
He can end this fight.
그는 이 싸움을 끝낼 수 있다.
I'm fucked.
난 망했어.
It's not like I did something bad,
내가 나쁜 짓을 한 것은 아니지만
but I'm in a holding cell.
하지만 저는 수용소에 있어요.
He's the guy from the bus, isn't he?
그 사람은 버스에서 나온 사람이지, 그렇지?
He's that crazy guy. Is he a junkie?
그 미친놈이군요 그는 마약 중독자인가?
Hey, there.
안녕, 거기.
I heard you pushed the bus over.
버스를 밀었다고 들었습니다.
Me?
나?
That wasn't me. I didn't do that.
그건 내가 아니었어. 나는 그렇게하지 않았습니다.
Look at this punk.
이 새끼 좀 봐.
He's totally nuts.
그 사람 완전 미쳤어요.
- Go ahead and push me too. - My goodness.
- 나도 밀어줘. - 맙소사.
I'd rather not...
차라리 안 할래...
- See? I knew it wouldn't be him. - He's no big deal.
- 봤어? 나는 그 사람이 아닐 것이라는 것을 알았습니다. - 그 사람 별거 아니예요.
He's nothing!
그는 아무것도 아니다!
Keep it down in there!
거기에 보관하세요!
I was keeping it down.
나는 그것을 억제하고 있었다.
I want to go home.
집에 가고 싶어요.
I just wanna take a shower, scroll on my phone, and get some sleep.
그냥 샤워하고 싶은데 휴대전화를 스크롤하고 잠을 좀 자세요.
I want to get to work safely tomorrow.
내일은 안전하게 출근하고 싶습니다.
I can't believe going to work is my wish now.
일하러 가는 게 믿기지 않아요 지금 내 소원은 이렇습니다.
God. Please help me.
맙소사. 도와주세요.
If you ever get into trouble, use this contact.
곤경에 빠지면 이 연락처를 사용하세요.
What's that idiot doing now? What's up with him?
그 바보는 지금 뭐하는 거야? 그 사람은 무슨 일이야?
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
CHAIRWOMAN PARK JEONG-JA
박정자 의장
JEONGJA LOANS
정자대출
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
My name is Kang Sang-ung.
제 이름은 강상웅입니다.
My father told me to call this number
아버지께서 이 번호로 전화하라고 하셨습니다
if I got into any kind of trouble.
어떤 문제라도 생겼을 때
And your father's name was?
그리고 네 아버지 이름은 뭐였지?
Right, his name is Kang Dong-gi.
네, 이름은 강동기예요.
Mr. Kang, Dong, Gi.
강동기 선생님.
GA TO KIM
가투킴
KANG DONG-GI
강동기
LOAN AGREEMENT
대출 계약
All right.
알았어.
Is your father well?
아버지는 잘 계시나요?
HOLDING CELL
홀딩 셀
Thank you.
감사합니다.
It actually worked.
실제로 효과가 있었습니다.
MY MIN-SUK (50)
마이민석 (50)
I'm dead meat.
나는 죽은 고기입니다.
Officer, the hero from the bus crash is here, isn't he?
버스사고의 영웅, 경찰관 여기 있어요, 그렇죠?
I'll explain everything again in the briefing.
다시 다 설명해줄게 브리핑에서.
- I'm sorry. - Mr. Kang.
- 죄송합니다. - 강 선생님.
Mr. Kang Sang-ung?
강상웅씨요?
Oh my.
아, 이런.
You've truly been through a lot.
정말 많은 일을 겪으셨습니다.
But who might you...
하지만 당신은 누구일까요?
JEONGJA LOANS
정자대출
Chairwoman Park.
박회장.
- Mr. Kang is here. - Chairwoman?
- 강 선생님이 오셨어요. - 위원장?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
- You're out of money, aren't you? - Pardon?
- 돈이 부족하지 않나요? - 뭐라고요?
Get in. I'll get you home.
타세요. 집에 데려다줄게요.
I probably shouldn't have called.
전화하지 말았어야 했을 것 같아요.
I saw the news.
나는 뉴스를 보았다.
You did something incredibly admirable.
당신은 믿을 수 없을 정도로 감탄할 만한 일을 해냈습니다.
Even I'm proud of you.
나조차도 당신이 자랑스럽습니다.
Anyway, how did you even think to call me in the middle of all that chaos?
그나저나 어떻게 나한테 전화할 생각을 했어? 그 혼란 속에서요?
First of all,
우선,
thank you for helping me.
도와주셔서 감사합니다.
You're also polite.
당신도 예의바르군요.
But you're curious
하지만 당신은 궁금합니다
to know how I know your father, aren't you?
내가 네 아버지를 어떻게 아는지 알고 싶어서 그렇지 않나요?
Honestly, I'm not curious.
솔직히 궁금하지는 않습니다.
Dong-gi owes me some money.
동기가 나한테 돈을 빚졌어.
A stranger is talking about my dad like she knows him well
낯선 사람이 우리 아빠에 대해 이야기하고 있어요 마치 그 사람을 잘 아는 것처럼
and mentioning his loan shark debt.
그리고 그의 사채 빚에 대해 언급했습니다.
It's somewhat surreal.
다소 초현실적이네요.
With the legal maximum interest rate,
법정최고이자율로는
the total comes to three billion won.
총액은 30억 원에 이른다.
The door...
문...
BEOMHA RANCH
범하목장
RESTRICTED AREA
제한 구역
MAN LIFTS FALLING BUS, PREVENTING CASUALTIES
남자가 떨어지는 버스를 들어 올렸습니다. 사상자 예방
Dad's going to like it.
아빠가 좋아하실 거예요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
How does it feel to be ordinary again?
다시 평범해지는 기분이 어떤가요?
Like being reborn?
다시 태어난 것처럼?
You should be thanking me.
당신은 나에게 감사해야합니다.
Is she dead?
그녀는 죽었나요?
No.
아니요.
Damn it. She's no fun.
젠장. 그녀는 재미가 없습니다.
Everyone's making such a big deal out of this.
다들 큰일을 하고 있구나 이것에서.
This is pretty.
이거 예쁘다.
- What happens if I get a shot of this? - Sorry?
- 이걸 찍으면 어떻게 되나요? - 죄송합니다?
Take it.
가져가세요.
The clinical trials are still--
임상시험은 아직--
Incompetent bitch.
무능한 새끼야.
You said the bus guy was broke, right?
버스기사가 파산했다고 했죠?
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
Make him even more broke.
그를 더욱 파산하게 만드십시오.
Then he won't be able to use his powers at all.
그러면 그 사람은 못 할 거야 그의 힘을 전혀 사용하지 않습니다.
Shall I cut him off financially?
그 사람을 재정적으로 차단할까요?
That's not fun. It's basically a battle of type matchups.
재미없어요. 기본적으로 유형 매치업 전투입니다.
Cash is just paper, right? Let's burn it.
현금은 종이일 뿐이죠? 태워보자.
Oh, that's right.
아, 그렇군요.
It still needs clinical trials, doesn't it?
아직은 임상시험이 필요하고, 그렇지 않습니까?
Hi.
안녕.
Can I ask you a favor?
부탁 하나 해도 될까요?
Damn it.
젠장.
Jeez.
이런.
Gosh, my head.
이런, 내 머리.
Excuse me?
실례합니다?
What exactly
정확히 뭐야?
is going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이야?
I need to see for myself
직접 봐야 해요
whether you've actually inherited it.
실제로 물려받았는지 여부.
Get started.
시작하세요.
I should've cooperated with the authorities
협력했어야 했는데 당국과
and faced the law's judgment.
법률의 판결을 받았습니다.
One thought came to me while being beaten.
맞으면서 한 가지 생각이 떠올랐습니다.
What the hell was Dad thinking when he told me to call this place?
대체 아빠는 무슨 생각을 하고 있었을까? 그가 나에게 이곳에 전화하라고 했을 때?
- Hey.
- 안녕. - 여기요.
Get up.
일어나세요.
What's with this punk?
이 새끼는 어쩌고?
- Did he pass out? - Is he dead?
- 기절했나요? - 죽었나요?
What's this? What's going on?
이건 뭐죠? 무슨 일이야?
What's all this?
이게 다 뭐야?
What's happening?
무슨 일이야?
I realized two things.
저는 두 가지를 깨달았습니다.
One. It did hurt, but not enough to kill me.
하나. 아팠어요, 하지만 나를 죽일 만큼은 아니다.
It's all thanks to the money.
다 돈 덕분이에요.
Two. If I spend all of it,
둘. 다 써버리면
that's when I'll really die.
그때쯤이면 난 정말 죽게 될 거야.
Damn!
젠장!
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
- Shit! - Jeez.
- 젠장! - 이런.
Damn you!
젠장!
Gosh.
이런.
You little...
너 좀...
What are you looking at? What?
무엇을 보고 있나요? 무엇?
Did you hit me? I swear...
나를 때렸나요? 맹세해요...
I'm struggling because I have no money.
돈이 없어서 힘들어요
It's exhausting.
지치네요.
Come to think of it, I've struggled and been exhausted my whole life.
생각해보니 고생했네 평생 지쳤어요.
Everyone out.
모두 나가세요.
So you did inherit it.
그래서 당신은 그것을 물려받았습니다.
How is Dong-gi doing?
동기는 잘 지내요?
In Spain...
스페인에서는...
He's traveling.
그는 여행 중입니다.
He skipped out with my money and is now traveling in Spain?
그 사람은 내 돈을 갖고 도망갔어 지금 스페인을 여행 중이신가요?
With that sly bitch?
그 교활한 년이랑?
If Dong-gi had married me like he promised,
만약 동기가 나랑 결혼했다면 그 사람이 약속한 대로,
he would have bought an island in Spain by now.
그 사람은 섬을 샀을 거야 지금쯤 스페인에서.
Anyway,
어쨌든,
including the cost of the test, the total is 3.005 billion won.
시험 비용을 포함해 총 금액은 30억 5천만 원이다.
You pay it back.
당신은 그것을 갚습니다.
Even as we speak, interest is piling up.
이야기를 나누는 순간에도 관심이 쌓이고 있습니다.
In addition to that damn superpower,
그 빌어먹을 초능력에 더해
the second thing I inherited was three billion won in debt
내가 두 번째로 물려받은 것 빚이 30억이었어
from a third-rate lender.
삼류 대출 기관
I'm sorry,
미안해요
but I think I should go home.
하지만 집에 가야 할 것 같아요.
- To discuss this with my dad first-- - Discuss what?
- 먼저 아버지와 이 문제를 논의하려면-- - 무엇을 토론하나요?
Then how about this?
그럼 이건 어때요?
If you're sorry, marry my daughter.
미안하다면 내 딸과 결혼해라.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
If you do that, I'll forget about the money.
그렇게 하면, 돈에 대해서는 잊어버리겠습니다.
Things are unfolding like a daytime soap opera.
상황이 전개되고 있습니다 주간 연속극처럼요.
If you become my son-in-law, you'll never be short of money again.
네가 내 사위가 된다면, 다시는 돈이 부족하지 않을 것입니다.
My daughter is so pretty because she takes after me.
내 딸이 너무 예뻐요 왜냐하면 그녀가 나를 따라다니기 때문이다.
Wow.
우와.
That must be nice.
정말 좋을 것 같아요.
You have a girlfriend.
당신은 여자 친구가 있습니다.
Are you hesitating because of her?
그 사람 때문에 망설이고 있나요?
That's not good.
그건 좋지 않아요.
Listen carefully.
잘 들어보세요.
If you leave like this,
이대로 떠나면
you won't even last 24 hours out there.
밖에서는 24시간도 버틸 수 없을 거예요.
If those guys get you, you're done for.
그 사람들이 당신을 잡으면 당신은 끝장입니다.
Who are those guys...
그 사람들은 누구입니까 ...
Didn't Dong-gi tell you?
동기가 말하지 않았어?
He's just as irresponsible now as he was back then.
그 사람 지금도 무책임해요 그 당시 그랬던 것처럼.
They're out there.
그들은 밖에 있어요.
Some serious lunatics you can't handle with your paycheck.
몇몇 심각한 미치광이들 월급으로는 감당할 수 없어요.
So be my son-in-law
그러니 내 사위가 되어주세요
and come live with me.
그리고 나랑 같이 살아요.
Wait, what is this...
잠깐, 이게 뭐야...
Third floor?
3층?
I think it would be around ten meters.
10미터 정도 될 것 같아요.
10,000 won for every two meters.
2미터당 1만원
So 50,000 won.
그래서 5만원이군요.
Hey!
이봐!
- Gosh! - Goodness!
- 이런! - 맙소사!
Don't push me!
나를 밀지 마세요!
I didn't. I was helping you.
나는하지 않았다. 나는 당신을 돕고 있었습니다.
Let him go.
그를 놓아주세요.
He'll be back once he runs out of money.
그는 돈이 떨어지면 돌아올 것이다.
Wow.
우와.
Goddamn it.
젠장.
Seriously.
진지하게.
- Why? - What happened?
- 왜? - 무슨 일이에요?
Were you here all night?
밤새 여기에 있었나요?
This is you, isn't it?
바로 당신이군요, 그렇죠?
UNBELIEVABLE BREAKING DOWN THE BUS CRASH
믿을 수 없는 버스 충돌 사고 분석
ALIEN? SUPERHUMAN?
외계인? 슈퍼휴먼?
UNBELIEVABLE POWER EYEWITNESS TESTIMONIES
믿을 수 없는 힘 목격자의 증언
INSANE POWER, WHO IS HE?
미친 힘, 그는 누구인가?
You've become famous.
당신은 유명해졌습니다.
This is...
이것은...
Let me explain. I can explain.
설명하겠습니다. 나는 설명할 수 있다.
Explain it, then.
그럼 설명해 보세요.
What do I tell her? How much do I tell her?
그녀에게 뭐라고 말해야 하나요? 그녀에게 얼마나 말해야 하나요?
I blew my mom's money, got arrested by the police,
엄마 돈을 날려버렸어요 경찰에 체포됐고,
then got caught again by a loan shark,
그런 다음 또 사채업자에게 붙잡혔습니다.
and ended up owing three billion won.
결국 30억 원의 빚을 지게 되었습니다.
How much did you use?
얼마나 사용하셨나요?
What was that money?
그 돈은 뭐였나요?
If I tell the truth, Min-suk will kill me.
내가 진실을 말하면 민석이가 나를 죽일 것이다.
- I asked you what that money was! - Mom.
- 그 돈이 뭐냐고 물었잖아! - 엄마.
- She gave me her savings pool money. - How much?
- 그녀는 나에게 저축한 돈을 주었습니다. - 얼마나 많이?
- Well, Min-suk-- - Forget it.
- 그럼 민석아-- - 잊어버려요.
- I'll ask Mother myself. - Wait.
- 내가 엄마한테 직접 물어볼게. - 기다리다.
Thirty
서른
million won.
백만 원.
I was walking out with the cash when an accident happened in front of me.
나는 현금을 가지고 나가고 있었다 내 앞에서 사고가 났을 때.
So I had no choice!
그래서 선택의 여지가 없었습니다!
Okay?
좋아요?
So-jeong is getting married. At Cheongdam Hotel.
소정이 결혼한다. 청담호텔에서.
Really?
정말?
She told me to come with you and catch the bouquet.
그녀가 나한테 너랑 같이 가자고 했어 그리고 꽃다발을 받아요.
- Then we should go. Let's go. - No.
- 그럼 우리 가봐야지. 갑시다. - 아니.
I'm not sure if I can.
내가 할 수 있는지 잘 모르겠습니다.
Then I'll catch it.
그럼 내가 잡을게.
- I'm good at catching-- - You idiot. You said you wouldn't use it!
- 나 잘 잡는다-- - 바보야. 안 쓰겠다고 했잖아!
You said your superpowers are useless!
당신은 당신의 초능력이 쓸모없다고 말했어요!
Min-suk.
민석아.
Min-suk. Just hear me out.
민석아. 내 말을 들어보세요.
Min-suk, I...
민석아, 나...
Min-suk! Just wait!
민석아! 그냥 기다려!
MIN-SUK
민석
Min-suk.
민석아.
Min-suk!
민석아!
Hey, Min-suk.
안녕, 민석아.
Please wait.
기다리세요.
Min-suk!
민석아!
No, seriously...
아니, 진심으로...
She could've just heard me out.
그녀는 방금 내 말을 들었을 수도 있습니다.
Please pick up.
픽업해주세요.
Come on. Please answer, Min-suk.
어서 해봐요. 대답해주세요, 민석님.
Wait. That's...
기다리다. 그건...
- Is this 911? - That's my place.
- 여기가 911인가요? - 거기가 내 자리야.
No.
아니요.
It caught fire, for real!
정말 불이 붙었어요!
If you leave like this, you won't even last 24 hours out there.
이대로 떠나면 밖에서는 24시간도 버틸 수 없을 거예요.
Tell them to hurry. Quick!
서두르라고 말하세요. 빠른!
If those guys get you, you're done for.
그 사람들이 당신을 잡으면 당신은 끝장입니다.
Some serious lunatics you can't handle with your paycheck.
심각한 미치광이들 월급으로는 감당할 수가 없어요.
What do I do now?
이제 무엇을 해야 하나요?
Who were those guys?
그 사람들은 누구였나요?
Should I turn myself in to the police again?
제출해야 할까요? 또 경찰에?
But what crime did I even commit?
그런데 내가 무슨 범죄를 저질렀나요?
What if I walk free?
자유롭게 걸으면 어떻게 되나요?
Should I go to the press?
언론에 가야 할까요?
But what if they think I'm crazy?
하지만 내가 미쳤다고 생각하면 어쩌죠?
I wonder if Min-suk is okay.
민석이는 괜찮은지 궁금해요.
MY MIN-SUK (20)
마이민석 (20)
Please pick up. Come on.
픽업해주세요. 어서 해봐요.
The person you called is unavailable--
당신이 전화한 사람은 통화할 수 없습니다.--
TO SANG-UNG
상웅에게
You're okay, right?
괜찮지 않나요?
Min-suk, everything is okay, right?
민석아, 다 괜찮지?
Why haven't I heard from you?
왜 연락을 받지 못했나요?
He'll come looking for his girlfriend.
그는 여자친구를 찾으러 올 것이다.
Even if people die,
사람이 죽어도,
bring Kang Sang-ung in alive.
강상웅을 살려내라.
Yes, it should be fine.
예, 괜찮습니다.
This one's gonna be fun.
이건 재미있을 것 같아요.
- What the hell? - What?
- 대체 뭐야? - 무엇?
What was that?
그게 뭐였지?
What the...
뭐야...
No.
아니요.
This way!
이쪽으로!
FIRE AT CHEONGDAM WEDDING HALL CHECKING FOR CASUALTIES
청담웨딩홀에서 화재 사상자 확인 중
Fire just reported.
방금 화재가 보고되었습니다.
A short while ago, at around 2:10 p.m.,
얼마 전 오후 2시 10분쯤
a fire occurred at Cheongdam Hotel in Gangnam, Seoul.
청담호텔에서 화재가 발생했습니다. 서울 강남에서.
The fire is not yet under control.
화재는 아직 진압되지 않았습니다.
So-jeong's getting married. At Cheongdam Hotel.
소정이 결혼한다. 청담호텔에서.
She told me to come with you.
그녀가 나한테 너랑 같이 가자고 했어
2 P.M., CHEONGDAM HOTEL
오후 2시, 청담호텔
The extent of the damage at Cheongdam Hotel...
피해 정도 청담호텔에서...
What is this?
이것은 무엇입니까?
...is still unclear.
...아직 불분명합니다.
- According to eyewitnesses... - Hang on.
- 목격자들에 따르면... - 잠깐만요.
MY MIN-SUK
마이민석
Answer the phone. Please pick up.
전화를 받으세요. 픽업해주세요.
The person you called is unavailable. Please leave--
전화하신 분은 부재중입니다. 떠나주세요--
Fuck. What do I do?
젠장. 어떻게 해야 하나요?
I don't have any money.
나는 돈이 없습니다.
Fuck.
못쓰게 만들다.
Sang-ung.
상웅.
I saw the news about the bus accident.
버스 사고 소식을 봤습니다.
TO SANG-UNG
상웅에게
It was a blurry image,
흐릿한 이미지였지만
but I knew it was you right away.
하지만 바로 당신이라는 걸 알았습니다.
I'm not sure where the money came from,
돈이 어디서 왔는지 잘 모르겠습니다.
but it must've hurt a lot, even after doing a good thing.
하지만 많이 아팠겠군요. 좋은 일을 한 후에도요.
I felt the same.
저도 같은 느낌이었습니다.
It was always like that.
늘 그랬어요.
I always wanted to do more for you and your mom,
나는 항상 더 많은 일을 하고 싶었습니다 당신과 당신의 엄마를 위해
but something always came up.
하지만 항상 뭔가가 떠올랐어요.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
I'm sorry, but this is incredibly urgent. I'm so sorry.
죄송합니다만, 이건 엄청나게 긴급한 일입니다. 정말 죄송해요.
Close this account.
이 계정을 폐쇄하세요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Things like that will keep happening to you now too.
그런 일이 계속 일어날 거예요 지금 당신에게도.
I always worked, thinking that you or your mom could be
저는 항상 일했어요. 당신이나 당신의 엄마가 그럴 수 있다고 생각
in the overturned car, the academy bus, or the burning building
전복된 차, 학원버스, 아니면 불타는 건물
I was rescuing people from.
나는 사람들을 구출하고 있었습니다.
SANG! UNG!
상! 웅!
Honestly, this job is unbearable unless you think that way.
솔직히 이 일은 참기 힘들다 그렇게 생각하지 않는 한.
Even if it's hard or scary,
힘들더라도, 두렵더라도
do not run from it.
도망가지 마세요.
The person you love is waiting for you.
당신이 사랑하는 사람이 당신을 기다리고 있습니다.
That said, here's one piece of advice.
여기에 한 가지 조언이 있습니다.
Never cash out your savings...
절대 저축한 돈을 현금으로 바꾸지 마세요...
or your housing fund.
또는 주택 기금
What the hell?
대체 뭐야?
Please help her!
그녀를 도와주세요!
Min-suk!
민석아!
Oh no, Min-suk!
안돼, 민석아!
What do we do? Somebody please help her! Oh my God!
우리는 무엇을 합니까? 누군가 그녀를 도와주세요! 맙소사!
I told you
내가 말했잖아
I'm good at catching things.
나는 물건을 잘 잡는 편이다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I thought I was gonna die.
나는 내가 죽을 것이라고 생각했다.
Hey, it's okay.
안녕, 괜찮아.
You're okay. It's all good.
당신은 괜찮습니다. 다 괜찮아요.
Where did you...
어디서...
get the money?
돈을 받나요?
I closed it.
나는 그것을 닫았다.
My housing account.
내 주택 계좌.
Are you insane?
미쳤어?
Please step back!
물러서주세요!
Step back a little.
조금 뒤로 물러서세요.
This way!
이쪽으로!
Head down. Move slowly.
아래로 향하세요. 천천히 움직여라.
Yes, come out.
네, 나오세요.
- Keep your head down. - Thank you.
- 머리를 숙이세요. - 감사합니다.
Yes, lower your head more.
그래요, 고개를 더 숙이세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Here.
여기.
MARRIAGE REGISTRATION FORM
결혼 등록 양식
WIFE, KIM MIN-SUK HUSBAND, KANG SANG-UNG
아내 김민석 남편 강상웅
Apply for housing in your name.
귀하의 이름으로 주택을 신청하십시오.
They say if we win the newlywed housing lottery,
사람들은 우리가 이기면 말해요 신혼집 복권,
we can keep it even after a divorce.
이혼 후에도 유지할 수 있어요.
If you're okay with it...
괜찮으시다면...
let's get married.
결혼하자.
As obvious as it may seem,
당연해 보이지만
I wasn't the only one in this world
이 세상에 나만이 아니었어
who could use superpowers.
초능력을 사용할 수 있는 사람
What is that?
그게 뭐야?
Someone I can't handle with my paycheck.
내 월급으로는 감당할 수 없는 사람.
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
Min-suk, step back for a bit.
민석아, 좀 물러서 봐.
What? Why?
무엇? 왜?
I still have some money left.
아직 돈이 좀 남아 있어요.
This is driving me crazy.
이것이 나를 미치게 만든다.
Sang-ung, be careful.
상웅아, 조심해.
Sang-ung!
상웅!
My money. Damn it.
내 돈. 젠장.
Damn, it's hot!
젠장, 더워!
Sang-ung!
상웅!
Damn it.
젠장.
Kang Sang-ung!
강상웅!
I don't know what you're trying to pull,
뭘 끌어내려고 하는지 모르겠어
but leave him alone.
하지만 그를 내버려두세요.
Hey!
여기요!
Back off.
물러서세요.
Damn it. Don't come near me.
젠장. 나에게 가까이 오지 마세요.
You set dangerous fires
당신은 위험한 불을 지폈습니다.
and threw things at people.
그리고 사람들에게 물건을 던졌습니다.
It's hot, you rude bastard!
더워, 이 무례한 놈아!
Damn bastard.
빌어먹을 놈.
Thank God you're alive.
당신이 살아 있어서 하느님께 감사드립니다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Sang-ung, where did you get that money?
상웅 씨, 그 돈은 어디서 났어요?
It's hot.
덥다.
What?
무엇?
Is it the wedding gift money?
결혼 선물 돈인가요?
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR WEDDING
결혼식을 축하합니다
So it was So-jeong's wedding gift money.
그래서 그것은 소정의 결혼선물금이었다.
God, no.
맙소사, 아니죠.
Sang-ung!
상웅!
Kang Sang-ung, stay with me, okay?
강상웅, 나랑 같이 있어줘 알았지?
You'll be okay. It's going to be okay.
괜찮을 거예요. 괜찮을 거예요.
Sang-ung.
상웅.
Over there.
저기요.
So you're Sang-ung.
그럼 당신은 상웅이군요.
Is your father well?
아버지는 잘 계시나요?
Who are these people?
이 사람들은 누구인가요?
What the hell had Dad been doing all this time?
대체 아빠는 무엇을 하고 계셨나요? 그동안?
Back in the day, your dad used to buy me a lot of drinks.
옛날엔 너희 아빠가 날 사주곤 했지 많은 음료.
Take slow breaths. Slowly.
천천히 숨을 쉬십시오. 느리게.
Bun-mi.
분미.
That bastard is using Hwa-jin's powers, isn't he?
저 새끼가 화진이의 능력을 이용하고 있구나 그렇지 않나요?
Yes, it seems like it.
네, 그럴 것 같습니다.
Wait a minute.
잠깐 기다려요.
Who...
누구...
The Society of Korean Superhumans.
한국슈퍼휴먼학회.
I hate this.
이건 싫어요.
I'm screwed.
망했어요.
I'm totally screwed today too.
오늘도 완전 망했어요
Subtitle translation by: Yun-hee Jang
자막번역 : 장윤희